We would just buy cool looking domains
so that we could have like a 100
character long vhost so that it says
like i.am.in.you.computer.tday
dot and just these we would have like a
whole message.
>> Best part of acting when you can just
you know critical think right.
[music]
Yeah, [laughter]
>> dude.
[clears throat]
>> Not sure y'all know this, but two of the
most respected hackers in the CTPB
community, Bus Factor and XSS Doctor,
are now running monthly hackalongs on
the CTB Discord. Okay, you got to check
this out. ctbb.show/isord.
We find bugs almost every time we hack.
It's crazy. And and oftentimes it's not
even the people running the hackalongs,
it's the the community members that are
hacking along with us. It you definitely
increase your chance of finding a bug by
being on these hackalongs. So check them
out. ctb.show/isord.
Join bus XSS doctor and yours truly. And
uh let's pop some bugs. All right, let's
go back to the show.
Sup guys, got the this weekend bug
bounty segment for you. Uh yes, we hack
dropped another great blog. Alex
Broommans, I tell you, man, what a
researcher. Um, this article that he
released that I want to cover real quick
called Python Pitfalls has some crazy
crazy stuff in it that I've definitely
missed in prior assessments. So, check
this out. The first one is in Python's
OS.Path.join, which I've seen many
times. So, in the example here, he says
os.path.join
passes in / user/uploads and then the
payload received from the user. Right?
Well, if you give it just an absolute
path, it just ignores the the prefix,
right? So, if you give it as arguments,
I'm trying to put this in audio for you
guys. OS.path.join
slash user/uploads is the first uh
argument, and the second is / etsy
password. That will resolve to slash
Etsy password. It'll just ignore the
prefix uh which is super crazy to me.
So, uh, yeah, don't even worry about
path reversals. You can just put in the
absolute path. Uh, very odd. Um, and
then there's also this one down here.
It's the same sort of situation. Uh,
which is apparently URL.parse.
URL join does the exact same thing but
for domains. So, consider this. You have
uh url.parse.url join. The first
parameter is httpacample.com
and then the second parameter is
httpevil.com.
So you're uh you know providing an
absolute URL. The output of that is
evil.com. It just removes the whole
example.com piece [laughter] which is
nuts to me. Um so Python's got some
crazy weird quirks. Apparently, you
should just be yeeting absolute uh file
paths and absolute uh URIs everywhere
into Python and it just will just accept
it. Um so check out this uh article.
We'll link it in the description.
There's lots of other good stuff in here
like pickle derialization and stuff like
that. Okay, so that's that. Um next is
actually a quick announcement that I
wanted to remind you guys. We talked
about it on the Google Cloud episode,
but um Google Cloud VRP is offering a
bonus to all critical thinking podcast
listeners. If you mention the podcast in
any rewarded report between now and the
end of April, you will get uh an extra
reward, either cash or swag. Um so
definitely want to do that. So drop some
love for us in those cloud reports you
guys are putting in and get yourself uh
some swag. All right, that's it. Let's
go. Let's jump to the main show.
Dude, Tommy, man, I've been looking
forward to this episode for a long time,
and this is a special episode for me, as
you guys know, because Tommy is a part
of my hacker origin story, uh,
especially in the Bug Bounty world. So,
dude, I owe you a debt forever for
introducing me to Bug Bounty that day.
And the reason that happened was
>> Yeah, [laughter]
true. But the reason that happened was
you just showed up at my
VCU college cyber security club and
we're just talking about Bug Bounty
randomly. How do you even remember how
that happened?
>> Whoever the president was, I don't
remember his name at this point.
>> Parker. Yeah.
>> Yeah. So, he had emailed me or reached
out to me on Twitter. I don't remember
which one it was.
>> And he had asked me um if I would come
and talk to you guys about it. And I was
like, "Yeah, I guess." I had absolutely
no idea what to expect. I wasn't
expecting uh like 10 nothing against
y'all, but kids standing in a
>> What was it? It was like a computer lab.
>> Computer lab. We We like grabbed a
corner and stuck like a server rack in
there.
>> Yeah. And Yeah. I wasn't expecting what
it ended up being, but it ended up
working out. I had let um both uh Hacker
One, Bug Crowd, or I guess all three,
Hacker One, Bug Crowd, and Senate. I
[clears throat] had let all three of
them know that I was going to go be uh
going to be doing it and asked each one
of them to send me some u stickers and
swag and stuff to get out. I think
Hacker One was the only ones that
actually did.
>> Yeah, you sent us gave us some good
stuff.
>> Bug Crowd and uh Synynic didn't or they
couldn't end time something. I don't.
But um yeah, he emailed me or DM'd me on
Twitter. Has to do it. And since y'all
were local, I was like, "Yeah, anytime."
Cuz it's like 10 minutes from my house.
>> Sure. I'll pop in there.
>> Yeah. Whenever.
>> Well, it's funny cuz I was running, you
know, he was my co-president and I was
running the the labs at that time, you
know, and then you just showed up, you
know, and I was like,
>> he didn't even tell you about.
>> He didn't even tell me.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, man.
>> And then he didn't even come.
>> Yeah.
>> He didn't even show up. [laughter]
>> Shout out to Parker, man. I don't know
if you're listening, but uh that was the
most poorly organized thing that had the
greatest impact. Um so yeah, definitely
grateful for that. Well, um you know how
we do it here on the pod. I guess we
didn't even really talk about this
beforehand, but typically on on the
podcast, what we do is have guests bring
a vulnerability that they want to talk
about, you know, and and give us a
little uh summary just to, you know,
prove some expertise. Obviously, Tommy
Devos, guys, we don't have much to prove
here. Uh, a legend, but if you have
anything you want to a bug you want to
run by us or you can talk about your
more recent fuzzing stuff or
>> um
>> Well, the fuzzing I can't talk about the
bones yet. It hasn't been long enough to
where I'm allowed to disclose them,
right?
>> And I don't really want to make Google
mad.
>> Yeah.
>> I like them being nice. Um,
I guess
my favorite bug is still from Yahoo in
2018 that bought me my GTR.
>> Um, I was in Las Vegas in
October 2018. I had like moved out there
halfway for most of 2018. And um, I was
waiting for my friend Steve. We were
going to go do something at night. I
don't remember what it was, but uh he
was taking a shower and he was like a
I don't want this to come across the
wrong way, but he took forever to get
ready like a girl. Like it took him
almost two hours to take a shower, do
his hair and everything. And it's like,
dude, no. But I was bored and I went and
took out my computer and I was sitting
on his um kitchen table and I didn't
want to start hacking on anything new
because it's like I only had a little
bit of time.
could have had 15 minutes, could have
had 2 hours.
>> Yeah, exactly. And I don't want to get
into something and then have to stop it.
Like this morning, having to walk away
from the computer was driving me nuts.
>> I'm so sorry, dude. Not like literally
he popped an RC on one of his bugs as he
was walking out the door.
>> Yeah. Like I literally did it and then I
had to walk out the door. But I was
worried about doing that back when I was
at his house. So, I went and opened up
my Hacker One reports and just picked a
random SSRF from Yahoo and decided to
start playing with it. And I had had all
kinds of success in coding the IP
addresses in different ways to bypass
because they used a blacklist. They
didn't use an allow list. They used a
blacklist and blacklist are very, very,
very bad. [snorts]
>> Well, I don't even know why it worked,
but I was super stoned. So I decided
that I was going to take the AWS
metadata IP and instead of encoding the
entire thing, I took just the first 169
and octal encoded that left the rest of
the IP the same and it worked for some
reason. I have absolutely no idea why
you why logically it shouldn't have
worked. Yeah. And I was just trying
things because I was trying to pass
time. Well, it worked and I got the AWS
um credentials again. Oh my gosh.
Then I went back into my reports and I
pulled every single SSRF that I had
against Yahoo from the last three years
>> and it worked on every single one of
them. So I went and filed 18 new reports
each for each one of them was a unique
location and everything, but
>> they needed to go and update their deny
list again. And they paid me 10 grand
for each one. So I got the 180 grand and
then
>> that's nut. Four days later, I flew back
here to Richmond and
sat outside of the dealership that had
my GTR until they were open at 10:30 in
the morning and told them that it was
mine now.
>> Wow, dude. That's [laughter] crazy. So,
so you had um you went back to all of
your previous reports. So that's one I
think that's a great takeaway for the
listeners as well is like if you do have
a short amount of time perhaps to hack,
go back and look at a report that you
think you may be able to bypass or
something like that because then you
don't have to find spend time finding
something interesting.
>> Yeah, exactly. It's a It's a great way
and I mean things change. So even if
it's not bypassing the old
vulnerability,
>> they might have added new functionality
to the exact same little area that you
can quickly play with and you already
know
>> at least enough about it to find some
vulnerability. So anything that's
different there, it's it's less of a
learning curve to
>> to translate from not doing anything to
instantly being excuse me to get in
there and hack.
>> Right. Right. Make sure you don't bump
your mic when you're when you're doing
that. [laughter]
Um, yeah, dude. Totally. I think that um
I think that the technique is really
interesting, too, because obviously, so
just to speak it out, you know, plain
and clear, you had an SSRF, you were
going to hit 169.254.169.254,
which the AWS metadata endpoint, which
was going to drop back the access
credentials.
>> Yeah, because I had already done it in
the past, so I already knew the exact
path and the key name and all of that
stuff. So I was just trying to find a
new way to represent the IP address that
they hadn't accounted for.
>> Nice. And and the way you did that was
taking that first 169 and
>> just the first one because if you did
any of the other ones it wouldn't work
or if you did the entire IP it wouldn't
work. It had to be the first 169 for
some reason. I
>> I'll have to look that up. I'm not sure.
But I imagine what happened there is
that when you
had that first octet encoded with four
characters rather than three, right?
Octal, it's like
>> it's like 02. It was like 0
>> 526
or something something crazy like that.
Like it doesn't even when you're looking
at it, it doesn't even look like it's a
valid IP address.
>> Wow.
>> But
>> that's crazy, man.
>> According to Yahoo, it was at least.
[laughter] And I actually just saw
recently um within the last two weeks I
saw some other kid on Twitter post that
he did the exact same thing. Not to
Yahoo, it was for somewhere else,
>> but he did the exact same thing like
just a couple weeks ago and it's still
working. So, it's still something that
is valid today. It's still one of the
things that I try anytime I find
something that I'm going to test for
SSRF.
>> Wow. Nice, man. Good bug. I think that
uh you were the first person and I don't
know if you were the first person to
discover it at all, but you were
definitely the first person I heard talk
about the AWS metadata URL as well and
also this octal encoding. So uh for a
lot of the bug bounty community I think
that was uh you know you were the
introduction into that
>> for the octal maybe like I remember the
first time I hit the AWS server was
actually on Yahoo as well. I was sitting
in AWS reinvent up in DC.
>> Yeah, that's right. Yeah. Yeah.
>> I had gone up there because me and a
friend of mine here locally, Josh, we
had started a company here in Richmond
for security
>> and um we wanted to go up there as part
of the company. It was right before or
right when I was leaving my previous job
and getting ready to do Bug Bounties
full-time. And that's where they taught
me about the metadata server. I had no
clue what it was. and I'm sitting in a
in a talk there with my laptop next to
Josh and then they told us about the IP
and that it could be used to get the uh
the
>> access
>> access creds and everything and I was
like hold up. [laughter]
>> So then I actually sent Sam ZLZ a
message because we had been hacking on
Yahoo and there was this place in their
small business. You used to be able to
go and buy hosting and domains and stuff
from Yahoo Small Business and there was
a place on one of their main front pages
where you could give it a URL and it
would go take a picture of it for you.
>> Yeah.
>> And we used that to take a picture of
the AWS access credentials for us. And
that was the first time I'd ever gotten
it to work.
>> It's so funny you t talking about this
because I I don't remember very much
from that era at all of like what was
going on in life and stuff like that. I
remember everything that you just said
like it was yesterday, man. Like the
Yahoo domain I remember as well.
>> AWS stuff. I was like, "Wow, this is the
most interesting thing I've ever heard
and my brain just like clamped on it
like [laughter]
you know." Um, so very good times back
in the day watching you and Sam
terrible.
>> Oh, it was a lot of fun. It was a lot of
fun and they had st like we weren't even
finding anything crazy. It was just
stupid simple XSS's and stuff like that
because it
>> it's exceptionally hard especially when
you've got a website builder as part of
your product. It's exceptionally hard to
do that in a safe way. And
>> yeah, it took Yahoo a while before they
were able to do it. But it wasn't their
problem.
>> That was good scope. It was good scope,
man.
>> Yeah, I was sad when they took it out.
>> Yeah,
>> I was real sad. So, so you know, pulling
on that thread a little bit, like you
I've already talked about how you're,
you know, a part of my origin story as a
hacker, but also you were a strong
influence on Sam Sam Curry and Corbin
Leo, uh, and some of the other earlier
on hackers, um, that kind of popped up
in the scene and started, you know,
going to live hacking events and stuff
like that. Um, so I mean, was that
something that you were always trying
to,
you know, do intentionally or was that
just a part of you being early on in the
Bug Bounty scene, you think?
>> Um, a little bit of both. Uh,
I'm older than most of y'all by quite a
bit. And um it's been really important
to me to try and get
younger hackers, including all the way
down to kids like in middle school
involved in it. Um I got curious when I
was in
>> like late elementary, early middle
school,
>> so I know about when kids start getting
uh interested. So that's why I like
going and speaking at middle schools. I
haven't spoken at in an elementary
school. I don't think that would be
appropriate because I'm not sure that
the kids in elementary school are quite
uh
knowledgeable enough about computers as
a whole. Like they know how to open up
Roblox, right?
>> Or Minecraft. That's about it. But once
they're in middle school, they're
actually
>> have the ability to take classes,
programming classes, typing classes, and
that kind of thing. And they're actually
using computers more.
>> And I don't want them to make the same
mistakes I did. It's uh I have been
having this conversation a lot the last
couple of weeks, but when I started,
>> we didn't have virtual machines.
>> We didn't have a lab that you could go
like tryh hack and try to hack and all
of that kind of stuff. We didn't have
any of that. Our practice was the real
world. We had to go and hack real
systems. And if you wanted a challenge,
you had to go and make really stupid
mistakes in hack government military
systems.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Okay. So, let's let's go
down that path a little bit here. So,
that was a part of your origin, right?
You were a black hat earlier on and um
you know got got caught and kind of
reformed there. Do you want to give us
like the the you know five minute
version of that story so that we can
have that context?
>> Yeah. Um,
IRC was a fun place in the '90s.
>> We like to take channels from each
other. So, we built very very large botn
nets
um to dodos people and
you're I don't even know if you're old
enough to remember. There was this kid
in Canada named Mafia Boy
>> uh back in 99 2000. He is credited with
the first largecale DD dos attack when
he dodosed like uh
eBay and like the I don't remember all
the sites but it was any of the big
sites that were on the internet back in
like 2000. And he was actually the kid
we were fighting on Fnet for our
channels. He was a member of TNT and I
was with TDK those damn kids. and we
were constantly fighting over the
channels with him. So that botn net that
he used against like all the Fortune 500
companies all the time. He hit us with
it a lot and it would take us offline a
lot. But I spent a long time doing that.
I changed in about 2000. Thought it'd be
fun to deface websites. So I started
doing that.
>> When you were doing the botnetting, how
were you getting these compromising
these machines? Was it just rats? Are
you like
>> No, no, no. There was no concept of
that. No, like the only riot there was
at the time was uh like sub7 and then
CDC uh the cult of the dead cow put out
uh back orphice but and there they were
only Windows based.
>> Yeah.
>> When I was a hacker, we had a rule in
our groups. You weren't allowed to hack
Windows. It was too easy.
>> It was too easy. Dead ass. Don't mean to
cuss, but you weren't allowed to hack
Windows at all. We felt that hacking
Windows was too easy. Um, but every
system back then could be hacked.
Literally, there was no such thing as a
secure system, right? Because these
things were designed with how thinking
that somebody might want to break into
it over the internet. The internet was
still barely new. It was
10 yearsish old, maybe a little bit
less. So, it was it was a completely
different world. There was no such thing
as a web vulnerability. I don't even
think we had databases like for you to
store one of
>> Didn't have databases.
>> No, it wasn't a concept. It was stored
on disk. Like if you were to go to a
website and purchase something, they
would actually save your name, address,
credit card number, and all of that into
a text file on the [laughter] web
server. Like on the web server, all you
had to do was break into the web server
and go find like cc.txt txt and you had
a list of everybody's legitimate info.
>> That's crazy, dude. What a what a time.
>> And this was before we had those little
three-digit codes on the back. Like, I
remember being a kid and we had credit
card generators where you could
literally open up this tool, click a
button, and it would give you a credit
card number and an expiration date. It
didn't need the three-digit code because
that didn't exist yet. They created it
because of this fraud time period. I
bought probably a 100,000 domains. no
domains for like a dollar a piece
>> just by clicking this little button and
say, "Hey, generate me a credit card."
And it it would just generate one. You
didn't need any name or anything like
that. It was all you needed was the 16
digits and a fourdigit. Um
>> What a what a time, man. Yeah, because
they didn't they weren't connected like
they are now to
>> uh I don't even know the payment process
companies anymore, but they weren't
connected to them in real time to be
able to actually validate them and
everything like that. So, I think most
of the companies would just kind of like
>> if it was the proper format
>> and looked real, then they would accept
it and then they would find out a couple
of days later that oh, it wasn't valid
or something like that. So, but it was
with for domains
>> back then to go on IRC. We always wanted
a BNC and it was just a a V host. It
allowed us to hide our ISP and IP
address behind it. And you used to have
to pay companies each month for them to
create you a VHost because then they
would create you the Vhost and if you
paid them the $5 a month or whatever,
they would make that Vhost reverse DNS
to a certain IP address so that way you
could go on IRC with it and everything
and it all looked right.
We would just buy cool looking domains
so that we could have like a 100
character long vhost so that it says
like i.am.in.yoump
computer.
And just these we would have like a
whole message as our host name.
>> Wow, dude. What a what a time. So after
the IRC era, you kind of moved into
website to facement, right? And I
imagine that was your your intro into
like web vulnerabilities and stuff like
that.
>> No. No,
>> there were still no web vulnerabilities.
>> Okay,
>> there's no such thing.
>> so like that there wasn't like websites
back then were written in either
HTML,
>> static files or
>> Yeah, it was it was like I don't even
>> I don't remember if we even use
JavaScript.
>> Yeah, [laughter]
>> like I'm I'm trying to remember.
So would you just like use some network
level exploit to get access to?
>> Yeah, it was always it was always we
would route them through TNET SSH FTP.
>> Root them through TNET.
>> Yeah, TNET every TNET.
>> Uh Solaris, which is Sunos, whatever you
want to call it. Um all versions of BSD,
>> FreeBSD, NetBSD, BSDI, OpenBSD.
Uh I think there was one more too. I
think there was like five of Would they
just leave TNET open like or would you
have to use a Tnet exploit or what?
>> You would use a TET exploit. But you got
to remember something.
>> Everything had TET back then.
>> We SSH was new. SSH was new in the
mid mid 90s. I want to say mid to late
90s was when it was starting to be
adopted and it was significantly more
common for them not to have SSH than it
was for them to have SSH. So everything
was TNET. So the the whole process was
use a TNET exploit or whatever the
exploit you wanted to use whether it was
TNET we um RPCs RPCs on Unix boxes
listened on port 111 I think it is every
single RPC that listened on that port
had a remote root exploit every single
one printers name ser bind what
underpins our name server that had tons
of vulnerabilities back in the day and
that was a huge target for us we always
wanted to compromise name servers Um but
we would compromise them and because
everybody was using Tonet we would
install packet sniffers key loggers on
it so that we could get the tone net
credentials of anybody that connected to
that machine and used it to connect to
others because we would target
university computers a lot. Um
Taiwan, Korea
and Hong Kong. those three countries
were
they were always farther behind like
most the rest of the world like we're
running Linux 5.2 two, they're still
running like 4.1, for example. So, they
were always running super old operating
systems that always had vulnerabilities.
>> Anytime you needed shells, because our
rule was you don't hack from your own uh
system,
>> right?
>> You never hack from your own system. So,
you would get either take the risk that
first time and hack something overseas
and get the access to that box or you
would get somebody to give you access to
a box overseas. And anytime we needed
shells, we would scan the entire class A
of 200 dot and 210 dot because there you
were guaranteed to get a few hundred
root shells over scanning those. We we
would write autorooters that would
>> Yeah, I was going to say how are you
routing traffic through these things
then? Are you just like hopping on by a
TN net and then issuing running the
exploits from there or Okay,
>> that's all we would do is uh now
starting in the late 90s and early 2000s
we weren't using tonet anymore. We were
using backward versions of SSH so that
way it was encrypted and we would have
our rootkits installed so they couldn't
see anything that we were doing and have
our hidden directories and everything
and we would just use those
>> essentially as a jump box. We would use
those to do the hacking and do the
connecting because back then we figured
that
it would just be a lot harder for them
to
the websites that we hacked would trace
it back to that Korean or the Hong Kong
or the Taiwanese server and then we were
banking on the fact that they weren't
technologically advanced enough to be
able to trace it from there back to us.
>> So So I mean that sounds like a good
play, man. How did you how did you guys
get caught? Oh, people tell.
>> Yeah, people talk.
>> Yeah, that's the
that's what it always just about came
down to. Um, Cowhead got arrested
because of Defcon in 01 at the Alexis
Park. Um, you know, they have the little
um scavenger hunt. Well, the scavenger
hunt that year took you to a uh pay
phone that was 24 karat plated gold on
the wall.
>> Wow. He ripped it off the wall and took
it to him instead of taking them to it
because you got to remember something.
We didn't really have camera phones back
then. So, you couldn't just take a
picture with your phone and show them
you found it.
>> So, instead of taking them to it, he
ripped it off the wall. He got arrested
at Defcon.
>> We all went home a week later. He puts
on our website. He makes Rafa makes a
graphic for him and then he puts it on
Kowed put it on our website and it was
bragging about him getting arrested at
Defcon for ripping the pay phone off.
The FBI monitored our website. Duh. So
they saw his post. They went to Las
Vegas said, "Hey, tell me who you
arrested during this week for doing
this."
>> Oh no.
>> They gave him his information in
Tennessee. So they went to Tennessee and
he was 15 years old. I had broken into
the uh
>> Wait, Cowhead was 15 years old at this
time.
>> Yeah.
>> What? How did he get Did he live in Las
Vegas? How did he get to death call?
>> That's what I'm getting ready to uh
explain.
>> Oh my god, this is crazy.
>> Um I'd broken into the Utah DMV computer
systems
>> so I could actually create fake IDs. But
mine, if you got pulled over by a cop
and handed them your ID, you were okay.
because I would actually put you into
their system.
>> And yeah, all of us had an ID that said
we were 22. I wasn't, but 17, almost 18.
>> Oh my gosh. And and your parents were
just like
>> Oh, they didn't care.
>> They were just gone. You're just like,
"Hey, I'm going to a conference. Bye."
>> No, I didn't even It wasn't even that.
It was just I left. Like from the time I
was like,
>> man,
>> 13.
>> From about 13 on,
I could pretty much do whatever I want.
Like I got expelled from school in 2000
and my punishment was I went on vacation
for a month in uh New Mexico with other
hackers.
>> Oh my gosh.
>> So well that is uh that is one way of
doing it I guess.
>> Yeah.
>> So okay so he gets he gets caught. They
monitor the FBI site or the FBI monitors
that site. They track him down and then
>> he was only 15.
>> Yeah. He had pictures on his computer of
him and his girlfriend who was also 15.
>> So
>> yeah, people don't understand, right,
>> that that still counts as child
pornography,
>> right?
>> So they threatened him to charge him
with possession of child pornography,
even though it was him and his
girlfriend consensual and all of that.
>> They threatened to charge him unless
he's hold on us. So he's hold on
everybody. He didn't know enough about
me to know where I lived or anything,
>> but he knew enough about one of our
other members, Noid.
>> And
uh Noid actually lived over in
Charlottesville.
>> Oh, really?
>> Yeah. Me and Noid went to King's
Dominion and stuff a few times together.
And they caught No when he was boarding
an airplane to go, he was Brazilian and
he was boarding a plane to go back to
Brazil because we had found out Cal had
gotten busted and they caught him when
he was getting ready, like literally
getting ready to board the plane. Wow.
>> He knew enough about me,
>> right?
>> So out of the 13 members of the group,
there was only one that didn't tell me
that was Rafa.
>> Wow, dude. That is a That is a crazy
time just trying to like put all that
together in my head. It's like you guys
were so young.
>> Yeah,
>> that's nuts. And boarding planes and
like create crafting these fake IDs and
like that's nuts, man.
>> Yeah, it was it was a fun time. Like I
had a lot of fun back then and I
wouldn't change any of it.
>> So So you got caught. You went away for
a little while. How how long were you in
prison? And And
>> the first time, two and a half years.
Mhm.
>> And then I came home and when I got
expelled from school, they banned me
from touching a computer because one of
my charges during the expulsion was for
computer hacking as well. So they banned
me from computers.
>> And then when I got released in ' 06,
I'm not a fan of people telling me I
can't do something,
>> right?
>> So I didn't listen. I stayed off a
computer for like a month. Mhm.
>> By February, I was back on the computer.
>> It It's got to be torture, man. Like
>> especially being like
I'm ADHD.
>> The only thing that can keep my interest
is computers and hacking and security.
So, it was like
>> I was working [__] jobs as
>> construction. I was a chef for a little
while and it was just boring. I hated
it. Yeah. I started getting back on the
computer again. I started
I joined another group called Core
Project
>> under a different name that time. Uh and
defaced a few websites again. One of
them was Yahoo. They got real mad at me.
It was biz.yahoo.com.
>> And um
uh for that one,
I wasn't allowed on computers. My
probation officer would show up at my
house randomly, like at least once a
month.
>> He had come over like a week before. So,
I was like, he's not going to He had
never come again for at least three or
four weeks in between visits.
>> So, I figured that was good.
>> I was sitting on my computer one day and
I had my computer set up in my room so
that I there was the walls were like
this. My computers were right here and I
was sitting right here facing this way.
But literally right beside me, I had two
giant windows like double the size of
this window right here.
>> Yeah.
>> So that I could look straight out into
my driveway. And my driveway was pretty
long. He had to come into the driveway
and then turn and come down a little
bit, turn again, and then come back up.
>> So you'd have some time.
>> So I had some time.
>> I see him pull in like starting to pull
into the driveway and I panic. Yeah.
>> I jump up out of the chair, start taking
>> Laptops weren't as prevalent back then,
so it was always desktops.
>> So, I start ripping everything apart. I
take the keyboard and the mouse, throw
it onto my bed. As I'm taking the tower
out, I don't remember where I hid the
tower, but I hid the tower somewhere in
the house. Came back, got the monitor,
hid that somewhere else.
>> These things are heavy as [__] at that
time, too. [laughter]
>> Yeah, they were.
I forgot to grab the keyboard,
>> the freaking keyboard, man.
>> Off the foot of my bed.
>> Ah,
>> probation officer comes into the house
and one of their things that they do is
a inspection. So, they walk through
every single room of the house and look
through every they aren't allowed to
actually search search, but they can
come in and anything that is within
their view, they're allowed to use
against you.
>> So,
>> damn it, dude. He had me walking him
through the whole house and opening the
closet so he could peep his head in and
everything. And we got up to my room and
the keyboard was sitting on my on my bed
and he used that as saying there was
enough uh probable cause to say that
>> to search or something or
>> no to consider me in violation of
probation. Go
>> because there was no reason to have a
keyboard if I didn't have a computer. So
he violated me on my probation. And the
funny thing is he gave me my little
violation hearing for like the next
week. I went to it.
I had been doing a lot of drugs,
>> but I was using these drinks and pills
that are supposed to clean your system.
>> And I was having to take a drug test
three times a week.
>> And I was taking these and God said to
your body, man.
>> They never said nothing to me. Right.
When I went to court for my violation,
they called me out. I had failed 17
tests in a row for cocaine.
>> Yeah. [laughter]
>> I passed them all for weed
>> and I took every test high. So the
drinks and pills I was using, it was
these um these like cleaning things that
you take it you drink 32 ounces of water
and you're clean for six hours. I was
taking those. They're just like little
detox things
>> and they worked for weed. They didn't
work for coke and I had no idea until I
show up and the judge is like, "Yeah,
well, you've got 17 violations for a
failed drug test for cocaine." And then
for
>> And they never told you once?
>> They didn't tell. No, not until I was
there,
>> dude.
>> So then they gave me another year. So I
went back to prison for a year or a
little under a year and then I got out
again in
uh in late 2008, I think it was.
So then that time I was I was good when
I came home that time. I didn't go back
to hacking. I got an Xbox and started
playing Call of Duty which I wasn't
allowed to do. I wasn't allowed to have
a game system.
>> I was going to say like dude that's
computer violation.
>> And then um I started playing a browser
based game. My sister had come up from
Florida to visit with her fiance at the
time
>> and um he was playing this game called
Hebony
>> and
>> Oh yeah, dude.
>> Yeah. So he showed it to me and was
telling me about how people were finding
exploits and stuff like that in it. They
were making money selling resources. So
I was like, I'll give it a try. I wrote
the first B.
>> You said you were good, dude. Hold up.
You said you were being good.
>> I was just playing games. I wasn't
hacking anything. Oh, sure. Okay.
>> I was just playing games,
>> but I wrote the first bot for Ebony
>> and then
um there was a business two doors down
from me at this time and they got broken
into and the only thing that was stolen
was computers.
>> Ah,
>> the cops in handover, they know my
history. I mean, I've been
>> running in with them for a very long
time at that point.
>> And um they swore up and down it was me.
Rafa was also doing blackhead hacking
again from Venezuela and he had somebody
in America working with him. They swore
that was me. So they watched me, the FBI
watched me for 6 months and could not
>> get any evidence against me.
>> So then they used the burglary at the
business two doors down as an excuse to
raid me and look for those computers and
then find anything else they could lock
me up with. M
>> so I was up playing Evony until 5:30 in
the morning on no October 8th of '09.
I went to bed and laid down between 5:30
and 6 and the next thing I know it's
6:15 and I hear something banging on the
door. So I went downstairs and I peeped
around the corner cuz we had those glass
things beside the door so you could see
outside.
>> Yeah. And I could see people standing
out there, but they're beating on the
door saying
>> police get out the house. I live like at
the time I lived like two miles from a
jail.
>> Yeah.
>> And people escape from it every once in
a while. And when they do, they search
our areas and I thought somebody escaped
from the jail and they were like in my
backyard or something.
>> Oh my gosh.
>> So I go and open the door and they bust
through that door.
>> They bust through the door with their
M16s. They handcuffed me and this is in
October. It was cold as hell. I'm in
just sweatpants cuz I was in bed.
They've got me handcuffed for over an
hour laying on face down on the floor in
my living room while they secure the
house
>> and then they found a few computers here
some Xboxes and stuff like that. So they
sent me back for a year and a half that
time. But it was the reason they sent me
back for a year and a half was because
they were trying to build a case against
me for doing stuff with Rafa again. And
I kept trying to tell them, "Every time
y'all have ever come and arrested me for
something,
>> once y'all get to the point where you
show up at my house,
>> it's too late to deny it. They know it
was you if they ended up at your house,
you know, if you're actually the one
that did it." So, I've always been
honest. Like you come and kick my door
in and say, "Hey, were you hacking
this?" I mean, you just kicked in my
door. I'm going to admit it because I'm
going to try and not get in as much
trouble, right? You have at least enough
that led you here. I kept trying to tell
them that it wasn't me and they didn't
want to believe me. So, they gave me
>> what was it 16 months, 15 16 months that
time to build the case. And then four
months into my sentence, they came and
visited me and apologized. [laughter]
They found the person that had broken
into the business to
>> Doorstown
>> and they had found the person that was
working with Rafa that was happening
with Rafa. So I asked them, "Hey, does
that mean y'all are going to let me out
of here?" And they were like, "Well, you
were still in violation of your
probation for having the game systems,
cell phone, and the computers. But
>> they killed my probation."
>> Okay.
>> So, and they removed the limitation that
I I was banned forever from a computer.
[snorts] and they removed that from me
kind of as like their apology for
sending me back. So,
>> that's a great a great uhation there.
>> It ended up working out cuz otherwise I
wouldn't have been able to do bug
bounties or anything. Otherwise, I still
probably would have done it, but I would
have just gotten in trouble
>> and then you would have this uh year in
prison every couple years.
>> It's life. If I get in trouble again for
computer crimes, it's life. That's why I
>> That's why you're really really
>> That's why I yell at people all the time
about scope. They don't understand the
only reason bug bounties are legal is
because the company says yes, you can do
this if you follow these rules. If you
follow if you deviate from those rules,
what in any way, shape, or form, there
is absolutely nothing you can do to
prevent a CFA violation. All it takes is
one pissed-off chief legal officer one
day or one company to be having a bad
time and then you go out of scope and
them just say, "All right, you know
what? Screw it." And they go after you.
And it's like,
>> just because it hasn't happened yet,
doesn't mean that it can't. And I'm not
willing to take the risk that it would
be.
>> Let me ask you your take on this then
because you've you've hacked with Sam a
good bit. Sam does a bunch of like
just I'm going to hack this company and
do a write up about it under the name of
security research and he you know I've
talked to him about it at length and
he's like I'm I'm pretty sure it it's
under this like fair usage policy of
these websites you know for security
research purposes and I say dude I
wouldn't do that
>> only if if they explicitly have a VDP
>> or bug bounty program. Yeah,
>> you're legal.
>> If they don't and you do not have
written permission, it can't even just
be them, you know, a friend that works
there and he said, "Yes, you can." No,
you have to have written all. It's no
different than a pentest. If you're
going to go pentest a company, you
wouldn't pentest them without having
scoping documents over what you're
allowed to hack, what are your limits,
and everything. It's no different. So,
there's a lot of people that
will pick a random website. And my big
problem is when these, now I'm not
saying Sam would do this because I'm
absolutely certain Sam is smart enough
to know that if he finds a vulnerability
doing this, the first thing he does is
email security@comp.com,
not privacy at company or legal or
support [laughter]
trying to scare people.
>> That's a good uh annoys the hell out of
me. And the my biggest pet peeve is when
people claim to be experienced security
researchers and their first email for
something like that goes to privacy or
legal or randomass email addresses. It's
like, no, you're you're not an
experienced researcher or anything
because any any researcher knows.
Logically,
>> the first thing you do if you find a
vulnerability, check if they have a
program on a platform. If they don't,
you email security at Why am I going to
email their legal team to tell them that
their legal record is messed up?
>> Yeah, exactly. No, no, it's bad, man.
Okay. So, so I guess that's a good
transition though into Bug Bounty. When
did you first hear about Bug Bounty? And
um yeah. Well, let's
>> 2014 is when I first heard about it.
That's when I created my accounts on
Packer One and Bunk Crowd, but I didn't
do it. So, at that time,
>> do you remember how you heard about it?
Like,
>> um I want to say it was Twitter.
>> Twitter. because I was
extremely active as an anon but not in
like I didn't do online ops like I I
wasn't dodosing websites. I
>> sure
>> I I still consider myself an A9 but I
disagree with the route most of them
went. Yeah. I don't think breaking into
if your target is P Fiser for example,
>> I don't think you hurt Piser by breaking
in and stealing their customer data and
releasing that.
>> Right.
>> Cuz you hurt the end user. Exactly. And
anonymous.
>> That's my biggest complaint about anons
is that they they're accepted lateral
damage is a lot different than what I
would do. Yeah. Um, but
>> so you heard about Bounty via Twitter
and
>> Twitter made your accounts.
>> I made my accounts, but it wasn't worth
it
>> cuz it had only been at that point a
couple of years since told me it was
life in prison if I get caught hacking
again. Never heard of Bug Crowd, never
heard of Hacker One, and it seemed too
good to be true. And then late 2015, I
started seeing a post on Twitter that
were bug bounty writeups, like such and
such getting paid x amount of money for
a v vulnerability they found and
everything.
>> And then finally early 2016 and like
January, February, I was like, "All
right, you know what? I'm bored as hell
at work. Let's give it a shot." opened
up hacker one, tried to register, and it
said that an account already exists with
my email. I didn't even remember signing
up for the account. So, I recovered the
email or recovered the account, logged
into it, and went to the little
directory of the programs and I saw
Yahoo. So, I was like
>> said, h
yeah, I knew a little bit about Yahoo.
Um, and yeah, just started
gave it a shot. Yahoo gave me my first
bounty in March 2016, $300.
And then my next bounties after that
were for uh Hack the Pentagon.
>> Wow, dude.
>> And I'm pretty sure I finished first in
Hack the Pentagon. And
so
hacked Pentagon,
they advertised it a bit, gave us 30
days from all of May of 2016 to hack on
the fuse host and stuff like that. It
was supposed to be like uh a limited
event and all kinds. They would invite
us to it.
We assumed that if you got an invite to
the program that they had already done
whatever they needed to to clear you.
Found out after it ran and after they
owed me like 30 grand for
vulnerabilities that you had to pass a
background check in order to actually
collect the bounties. I got pissed.
>> Yeah.
>> I went to Twitter and
>> vented my frustration.
>> Oh no.
>> About finding that out. No, it ended up
working out. Um,
>> one of the people that was running the
program, she saw my post and hit me up
in a DM. She was like, I 100% understand
your frustration. Give me 24 hours.
>> Mhm.
>> And 24 hours later, she hit me up and
said, "You now pass background checks
and you are going to get paid. So now if
you do a background check on me, I pass
it."
>> Oh, wow. That's kind of crazy. Yeah.
>> Wow. Well, I'm I'm glad you got that
redemption opportunity there. That's
>> I was I was super mad because I spent
the whole month because I had just
gotten into it.
>> Totally.
>> I just gotten into it and they weren't
letting us hack the US military. Like
from my experience in the 90s and early
2000s,
>> the US government military were some of
the easiest to hack into. So, I was
really looking forward to doing that for
bug bounties. It's also one of the
reasons I stayed on sync for as long as
I did. I only I only did government
military targets on them. I left them
when their new legal team decided to ban
me from legal uh from government
military targets.
>> Oh man, you keep getting it, man. That's
that's crazy.
>> Um wow. All right, man. Well, how has
the bug bounty industry changed since
that time? Like I imagine back then it
was very fresh. I mean, do you think
things are more difficult now?
Obviously, there's more mass adoption,
but
>> um
I don't know that it's [clears throat]
more difficult.
>> It's definitely different because
there's so many more companies that are
doing it.
>> Um
there's a lot more competition, but I'll
be honest,
99% of the competition is not actually
competition for anybody that has any
kind of skill whatsoever. The vast
majority and it I don't mean any
disrespect to the people but the vast
majority of people that I see on infosc
Twitter and X whatever you want to call
it
they're never going to succeed because
they I don't think they have the right
type of thinking like anybody can run an
exploit but yeah I feel like you've got
to have a certain logical way of
thinking to figure out how to break
Because computers do everything logical.
They do exactly what they're told based
on certain conditions. And part of being
a hacker is figuring out how to break
that logic of what they're expected to
do. And just most people aren't
they just can't do it.
>> Yeah. I think there's something special
about it. I've been trying to like
figure out exactly how to call it, but I
the only thing I've landed on is like
reasonable attack vector ideation. You
know, like being able to look at a
system, look at the security boundaries,
look at the implementation and just have
enough understanding about computers in
general and about the logic of that app
to come up with a reasonably feasible
attack vector.
>> Yeah. But the problem is implement that.
>> The problem is a lot of times our
successful attacks there's no reasonable
reason they should have succeeded. Like
there is absolutely no reason this
should have worked. But it does. But
that's just one of those things that
even when we know something's not going
to work, we still do it anyway because
we have to see it. At least for me
personally, I have to see it for myself.
And
I
>> it doesn't make sense why a lot of it
works. But I I think there's more
competition. There are tons of really
great hackers out there, but the only
thing is like there's so many programs
out there that
you can realistically find a couple of
programs that you want to focus on
yourself and make decent money if you
really wanted to. But
>> I I will probably get to that so I'll
wait.
>> Yeah. Well, I I wanted to swing back
around to SSRF and and what attracted
you to SSRF as a vulnerability
originally because I think at the time
SSRF was not as popular of a
vulnerability early early on in the in
the bug bounty arena in the in the you
know offensive security world and and
then you know you kind of went down this
path and really raked Yahoo over the
coals with that. Yeah, it was my the
main reason was because I have a lot of
fun beating denialist, blacklist,
whatever you want to call it. Um, SSRF
is one of those
>> vulnerability classes that historically
the main way they try to fix it is to
blacklist whatever it is that your
report Yeah. Exactly. And there's just
so many different ways that you can
bypass it that it's it's just fun and
it's a challenge. It was back then.
>> It's not so much anymore because at this
point I've got a couple of dozen
different ways that I encode IP
addresses. And it's
>> if I find something, I'll script
something to run through and test every
one of my variations and things like
that. And if it doesn't work, then I'll
move on. Well, depending on the target,
if it's a target that's a big enough
target and everything, then I might pass
it off to AI at that point and say,
"Hey, I've tried all of this. See if you
can come up with absolutely anything
that should not work that ends up
working."
>> Yeah.
>> But I my main reason for SRF was because
I like beating the blacklist. It's just
it's fun,
>> dude. It feels freaking good, man. It
feels good to get around a list like
that, you know?
>> Yeah. It's like it there's no other way
to describe it than it's similar to a
high because you get that dopamine rush
and it's just like
>> you know other people looked at that
exact same endpoint too and when you're
like none of them were able to figure
this out and you were it's just one of
those things that's just like that much
better
>> and if the programmer sat there and said
oh this I'll get them I'll get them with
this little rejax you know and then
[laughter] they don't escape a dot or
something you know
>> or they forget get the little question
mark at the end and things.
>> Yeah, it's crazy, man. It's crazy. It's
a lot of fun. Um, sweet, dude. So, you
mentioned AI. How are you using AI
nowadays in your in your workflow? I
know you're just Well, adding a little
context, you're just coming back from a
little bit of a bug bounty hiatus, and I
know you're focusing more on fuzzing
now, but how do you see AI in your
workflow?
>> Um, I'm using it a lot for the exploit
development aspect of it.
>> Yeah. Um,
>> I imagine that's really helpful.
>> It is extremely helpful. Yeah. Um,
>> I am having it do most of the exploit
development, but I've got some
restrictions on my AI. They're never
allowed to delete files every couple of
minutes. They have to do a brain dump
into a file so that way I can read
through it because I don't want them
doing things 100% for me. I want to
learn how to do it.
>> Mh.
So, I've got them doing little brain
dumps explaining why they did something,
what they've tried that's failed. Like,
I don't want just the information on
what succeeded. I need to know what you
tried that failed as well so that I can
learn for the next time that I'm doing
this and everything. Um, I've started to
use it a little bit when it comes to
writing um my harnesses for the fuzzing.
um
trying to I've been targeting Chrome.
It's no secret that I've been targeting
Chrome. I've uh before I would go in and
find the functions that I wanted to fuzz
and I would just write a very very basic
fuzzer that would just call the API for
that function and fuzz that. But now
I I've ran into several instances where
I found a vulnerability, but it wasn't
reachable in Chrome. So, I've got AI now
where it builds my harness to
essentially mimic the exact same flow it
would go in go through if I were to load
it via a web page.
>> Okay. So, you just gave me a bunch of
information that we're not going to air,
but um so I guess the TLDDR of the
situation is you are focusing on a sub
technology within Chrome and
>> right now, yes, because I'm trying to
learn it. I've never done browser
hacking before. So, I'm I'm trying to
learn it. Like, I haven't even started
to learn about the IPC,
how they're passing things from one
sandbox to the next one and all of that
kind of stuff. And I haven't done
>> I've done almost everything that I've
done so far has been within the renderer
itself. I do have a
separate vulnerability that I actually
need your help with because I need you
run Windows. I think
>> I do. I'm running Windows there. Yeah.
>> So, I need to uh
>> to test a vulnerability for
>> I'm like 99% sure that I've got to use
After Free in Chrome, but it's only
>> uh reachable on Windows.
>> I tried installing a Windows VM and
>> no.
>> Yeah, it didn't. Yeah, I I couldn't
figure out where the start menu was.
>> Okay. So So you're you're using AI right
now to build these harnesses that
trigger certain code paths within the
code within the Chrome code base for
>> Yeah. follows the same path because when
it comes to Chrome, it's like they've
got all of these kind of protections and
validation so that as soon as you open
up a website, as soon as it starts to
load and everything before the first bit
of its loading, they're running all
kinds of checks like if there's script
tags, making sure that the the
JavaScript is legitimate, if there's
image tags, making sure there's valid
video, I mean images in there, video
tags, valid video and that kind of
thing. All through all of that and
figuring out that
just because there's a vulnerability
behind all of that, the vast majority of
them are blocked by the validation that
uh Chrome does before it ever can reach
the uh vulnerable Chrome uh code path.
So, I've got mine set up so that it
actually sends my
what do you call corpus? Uh
>> yeah,
>> my my my current test file. It sends it
through the harness and the harness is
designed to
>> first go through Chrome's validation and
then through the next step and then the
validation of whatever's in the actual
area because if it's going to fail
those, I can't actually exploit it. Do
you have that isolated or are you
hooking into Chrome and like loading up
HTML files or whatever in Chrome and
then
>> It depends. In some instances it's
isolated. Some instances I'm just
running like a pure C or C++ program
that calls the exact same methods that
Chrome does in the same order.
>> I see.
>> And then
>> I'm sure most people have seen by now
the CSS zero day that came out like last
week that was uh exploited in the wild.
I'm fuzzing for similar things to that
right now where I'm actually doing it
within browser as well. One of my AMD
machines, I've got 32 um Chrome
instances that are running and then
within them I wrote some uh little
custom JavaScript things that run in the
the web page on each each side that's
doing all kinds of testing. It it hasn't
found anything yet. I'm not even certain
that it's going to work,
>> but
>> but we give it a shot.
>> Yeah, I I've mean,
>> yeah,
>> you don't know if it's going to work
until you try it. So, I I've got to try
it.
>> Nice, man. Yeah, that that definitely
sounds like AI is helpful for all that
because it requires a lot of
>> isolation of code within the Chrome code
base. It requires
>> and it's a huge code base. It's a huge
code base
>> and that's something that uh is helpful
is making sure you understand
The AIs we have access to are good at
different things.
>> Yeah.
>> So
like for example, if I want to look at
the entire Chrome codebase,
>> I'm only going to use Gemini.
>> Yeah.
>> Gemini with your paid subscriptions and
the paid max or whatever it is that I've
got. You get like up to two million
tokens of context.
>> Yeah. You need that context to be able
to not forget when you're trying to have
it trace through hundreds of files.
>> Did you clone down the codebase? Are you
having it like navigate? Okay.
>> Yes, I've got
>> got it all down.
>> I've got probably
six different or like six unique
checkouts of Chrome. I've got an ASAN
Chrome, an MSAN Chrome, a Ubisand
Chrome, a a normal vanilla Chrome, a
debug Chrome, an exploit dev chrome.
[laughter]
>> Um, all like I
>> it's heavy, man. That's a lot of code.
>> It's heavy and it's hard as hell to
actually build Chrome from source. Oh my
gosh, there's so many problems and
dependencies. So I try and keep
absolutely everything in its own folder.
So that way because I mean if you're
when you're fuzzing if you find a a
crash and you might need um asan address
sanitizer in order to find it. Well if
your libraries and stuff weren't most
recently compiled with asan you might
have compiled them with mand memory
sanitizer. instead you have to go
through the entire process of rebuilding
it again. So I've got a different takes
time. Yeah, it takes hours sometimes
depending on your system.
>> So I've got a different folder for each
different version of it. And then I've
got I when I go through the process
initially on a new target, I go through
everything that it takes to build it for
every version that I need. And then I
build shell scripts that will
essentially be able to because
>> when you're fuzzing, you've got to you
change things a lot. Like every time I
find a vulnerability, I patch it
locally. I I don't want to sit there and
spend the next two days discovering the
exact same vulnerability over and over.
So, I patch it locally
>> and then continue fuzzing
>> and then because
>> it lets me get farther into the codebase
>> because everybody else that's fuzzing
it, if you're not patching it, you're
going to keep getting stuck at that
exact same spot and you're going to have
no way to know if there's more
vulnerabilities.
>> And with the patch reward program, you
you submit that patch get an additional,
you know, bonus. You know that that code
is getting implemented.
>> But not even just that, because
>> that's great. Google actually has it so
that even if I find a vulnerability, for
example, in a third party library that
Chrome uses,
>> but it's not reachable in Chrome,
>> I can still go to the upstream
maintainer.
>> Yeah.
>> Report the vulnerability,
put a patch in for it after 30 days. If
they accept my patch and merge my patch
in after it's been been merged in for 30
days with no like problems or anything
like that, you can go file it to Google
>> because they've got the concept of open
source. Uh
>> yeah,
>> forgot what it's called, but you can
>> the open source VRP thing. Yeah.
>> Yeah. anything that you can like you fix
that is uh a material enhancement to the
overall security of anything that Google
uses then you can get I think it's up to
like 15 grand you can get depending on
what the vaults are and stuff. So
>> yeah,
>> I haven't I haven't looked thoroughly at
this VRP very much, but yeah, there's a
ton of open source projects that they
Yeah, look at this. One of them uh
supply chain compromises can get up to
31K.
>> Yeah. Dang.
>> Yeah. And they like Google's got
>> I'm looking at you, man. Lupin, go do
this, [laughter] man. Run Depy on this
[__] Um Yeah, dude. They've uh they've
got a lot of stuff trying to care for
the ecosystem, I think. You know. Um
>> and then Microsoft is now trying to do
the same.
>> Oh, really?
>> Microsoft just made their announcement a
couple weeks ago. I guess it's been a
month or so ago now, maybe a little bit
more, where they're going to start
actually paying for thirdparty
vulnerabilities and stuff that they
hadn't previously because they want to
also try and help
>> uh increase the security.
>> I've heard I've heard Microsoft's upping
their game. I'm I'm excited to see more
from them.
>> I'm going to end up right now I've been
doing Google. My goal is to try and be
top three or five for Chrome VRP through
through this year. uh once I find a
couple more bones to at least see myself
up there.
>> It's crazy though, man, because some
some of these guys just drop like, you
know, fully fully built out, you know,
straight RC and just one, you know, but
like and then it gets like 250K or
whatever. It's like
>> Yeah. So, the max that mine the one that
I've been working on can get is like 55
because it's within the renderer. But
the one that I'm going to have you help
verify whether it's actually reachable
or not, that one could be more because
it's in a what do they call it? Uh
highprivileged sandbox process.
>> There we go.
>> So that one can get a little bit more up
to like 85.
>> How are you how are you determining what
se section what sandbox all this is in?
Are they
>> Oh, it's in the code. you just know um
>> like uh
>> there's the GPU sandbox, there's the
renderer sandbox, and then there's the
actual Chrome process itself.
>> And I've most of my vulnerabilities so
far have been in the renderer process.
I've got one in the GPU process. Um,
I actually found it because I was trying
to figure out if there was a way to
escape the sandbox with the
vulnerability that I've been working on.
There's not. I need a completely
separate vulnerability for it. But I did
find what I'm 99% sure is another
vulnerability. It can't be used for this
kind of chain, but it could be a
completely different unique reportable
one. So, you've got AI helping you parse
the codebase, build out these harnesses,
build out these shell scripts, sort of
helping you get into browser based
hacking.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, do you I mean, do you find yourself
doing a lot of the hacking via these AI
agents nowadays for this stuff or are
you doing what kind of stuff are you
doing manually versus having the AI
agents go do it?
>> So,
>> I'm not going to lie, I spend a lot of
time having AI agents go do stuff
nowadays. Well, they're doing a lot like
say I get a new crash, um, they'll be
doing a lot of the RCA for me, like
helping me trace through the exact flow
of
>> whatever it was that got there cuz
they're so much faster. Like, I can do
it. They can do it in two minutes where
it would take me an hour or two. So, I
naturally will have them do a lot of
that. Um,
I haven't gotten back into web hacking
much yet. I'm trying to. I'm just
struggling to get motivated and find a
program that I want to actually hack on.
>> Google's fun, man. Google is fun to hack
on. Especially for web, it is like it's
challenging, you know? Oh, yeah.
>> It's very hard because they're not using
a lot of just straight JSON. You're
dealing with a lot of protojon. you're
dealing with a lot of like, you know,
just arrays that don't have any keys,
you know, like, you know,
>> I've thought about looking at Amazon,
like I mean, not Amazon, Google, GCP and
stuff. I've toyed around with going back
to Amazon and doing some on Amazon. Had
a ton of success hacking with um
>> uh Sean and um
>> Jonathan.
>> Yeah. for a couple of those AWS events
we were doing. Made a decent amount of
money. So, I've thought about going back
to that. It's just hard to get motivated
>> to want to do that. And I'm having a lot
more fun doing the fuzzing right now.
>> Yeah, man. If you're having fun with it,
you know, that's that's the main game
for us at this point, I think. Right.
>> Yeah. Because it's like I
I don't want to say web stuff is too
easy, but it's not as much of a
challenge.
So my goal I like I want to attend home
to home one time. I want to compete.
>> I really want to do that.
>> That's why I am main the main reason
that I'm looking at fuzzing and bare
exploitation and stuff is because I I
want to do it just one time just to
prove to myself that I can do it.
>> Yeah.
>> So
>> dude, we should uh we should we should
do it, man. I I've talked about it on
the pod a couple times and I've had a
couple guys from pone to own on but um
you know obviously the binary
exploitation piece which is a lot of pun
to own is not a forte for me but I have
done a little IoT stuff and there is a
good amount of IoT and uh and web stuff
is actually really applicable to to
these systems
>> and some of the IoT systems it is for
sure because that a lot of times is
going to be your front door that you're
going in through. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So some of the guys I was talking
to were saying like yeah definitely like
you need to have a good skill set in
reverse engineering and and binary
exploitation but also like if you have a
really good web guy you know then that
would be helpful for a pontoon team
because uh because definitely there are
those exploits out there. The thing is
it's just got to be unauthenticated RC
which is like you know a tall order. Um,
so
>> yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. The my big problem with it is that
it's generally got to be unauthenticated
rce but also unsandboxed and everything
like that. Like if you want to go and
pop Chrome for it,
>> you don't get many points if it's rce
and the renderer. You need that actual
sandbox escape and full system
compromise and stuff.
>> It's tricky, man.
>> Yeah. My my my
goal is to compete in pone uh pone to
own at least once.
>> Yeah.
>> And I want to get the max bounty one
time for good. Well, I want the 250 for
a uh full sandbox escaped rce in a car.
>> That would be sick, dude. That'd be
super sick. Well, maybe we'll do maybe
we'll do a Richmond Pontto own team,
man. Me, you, Turbo, you know? Uh that
would be that'd be a fun one. All right,
dude. Well, that was uh that was quite a
run. I have to say those stories are are
very unique and uh thank you for the
part you played in the in the bug bounty
ecosystem, man. And and and for me
personally, like really I I know I keep
saying it over and over again, but when
I think back to that day in that stupid
little lab in VCU, like crazy to think
that that was such a juncture point in
my life.
>> Yeah. And it's
it's like we didn't do nothing but sit
there for what about an hour just
talking
>> looking at your bug bounty reports
>> talking about the different types of
bounties and bugs and companies and
stuff like that. It's crazy how
everything kind of evolved from that.
It's uh
>> Yeah,
>> it's nice. It's fun.
>> dude. Thanks so much, man.
>> No problem. Thank you. And that's a wrap
on this episode of Critical Thinking.
Thanks so much for watching to the end,
y'all. If you want more critical
thinking content, [music] uh, or if you
want to support the show, head over to
ctbb.show/isord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great highlevel hacking
discussion happening there on top of
master classes, hackalongs, [music]
exclusive content, and a full-time
hunters guild. If you're a full-time
hunter, it's a great time. Trust me. All
right, I'll see you there.